Hey, Ysa!
Let's just let her rest.
She most likely just entered her inner world.
Inner world, doc?
Whenever a personality takes over,
That's usually where Ysa goes,
And the other personalities are also there.
You know, Estong...
Ysa has a unique condition.
Of course, we want to make sure if...
You'll have a positive effect on her or make things worse.
You bring out the best of us.
Maybe...
Maybe this exhibit just isn't meant for me.
You're all too loud!
You're all too loud! Stop it!
I can't finish that all by myself.
What if it gets to the point where...
I'll start to like you more than as a friend?
We can't be more than friends.
You can't pursue me.
We can never be together.
You can't fall in love with me.
Estong...
Seems like
You don't like my cooking anymore.
No, Pops.
That's just what heartbreak does...
Food just doesn't taste the same.
Kuya...
I'll take this, okay?
You don't have an appetite anyway.
I could've accepted it, Pops,
If she had just said no.
But I wish she had told me why...
It wasn't possible.
Kuya...
Does it matter?
If she doesn't want to,
She doesn't want to.
You got friend-zoned.
I want this.
It's mine.
Uh...
Hey, hey, Kuya, Kuya...
I was just kidding, okay?
You know, Kuya...
That's just Ate Ysa
Playing hard to get,
Like Adel.
Hey, wait a minute.
Why? Do you have a thing for Adel now?
Didn't you say she doesn't even reply to your messages?
And she's always so annoyed with you.
So you got seen-zoned after all.
And you got "annoyed-zoned", too.
Hold on, Pops. Why are we talking about me now?
Isn't Kuya the one who got rejected?
- Not me. - Hey, hey!
Whoa, easy.
I wasn't rejected, okay?
I only asked her if it was possible.
That's basically the same thing, Kuya.
That's enough, both of you.
Seriously, Estong...
So...
What's your plan now that you've been rejected?
Pops, I told you, I wasn't rejected, okay?
No, I was just asking.
Sorry.
You already know me, Pops.
I don't give up that easily.
Ysa, my dear.
Try not to think too much about what happened yesterday.
Don't overthink it,
Because it might be unhealthy for you, for all of you.
That's exactly what I was talking about—
That Estong would fall for her.
It's not just that.
I'm worried he hasn't really moved on yet.
What if you end up just being his—
Rebound?
A fallback.
Placeholder.
His safety net.
Something like that. Call it whatever you want.
I just feel guilty.
I didn't get to explain to Estong the real reason
Why I reacted that way.
I just walked away.
Why didn't you just tell him right away, to get it over with?
I just don't want him to think or feel that...
I only used him, or that I lied to him.
It's not your fault, Ysa.
I already made it clear to Estong.
I told him that if he started seeing you as more than a friend,
He had to let it go.
Love,
We all knew he wouldn't be able to help it, okay?
Truth is...
I should've put a stop to it right from the beginning
And told him the truth.
Nang, don't.
Please don't.
Let's just let it be.
I don't want things to get even more complicated.
I'll just avoid him, and then...
It will stop there.
That's right, Pops.
Kuya has done this before.
He kept hoping his ex, Ate Jean, would come back,
Even after everyone kept telling him it was over.
How much more now,
When he's only been rejected once by Ate Ysa?
You really took our saying to heart.
While there's still breath in us...
There's still a fight in us!
So it was your fault after all.
But
Remember this, son...
We all know that Ysa has a...
Special condition.
So how you treat her and care for her,
Should also be special.
Especially when it comes to her emotions.
I already know that, Pops.
Go on, eat.
Take back what you took from his plate.
Kuya, he told me to take back what I took from your plate.
And then, put it in mine.
What?
I was the one who cooked the food, didn't I?
Ysa, next time...
If he keeps bothering you,
You don't need to explain yourself.
Just turn him down.
He'll understand.
Ysa,
Do you like Estong?
What?
If you do, let me say this again...
Let it go.
We're only trying to protect you from what happened before.
Alright, that's enough. Let's just eat.
Come on, eat, okay?
Did you put calamansi in this?
- Thank you! - Thank you!
Are you sure, Ate?
You're going to avoid Kuya Estong from now on?
So you're not friends anymore?
I have to.
He's difficult to talk to.
Hey, man, come on!
Ate, Ate! It's Kuya Estong. Hide now!
- Excuse me. - You're so annoying.
- Where will I go? - Just hide!
Hide now!
What an idiot.
Hey, wait! Stay right there!
I have a cough.
I'm really sick, and it's contagious. Stay back!
You'll catch it!
- Go on. - Wait, is Ysa there?
- I just want to talk to her. - No.
No, no you can't.
I got her sick.
We might start a pandemic.
Do you want to get sick too?
Just leave!
Can I at least see her?
- I just want to check on her. - You can't. It's really contagious!
It's really, really bad!
As in!
We're really sick so just go, Kuya!
You're not allowed to see her for days or even week.
You really can't!
- Oh, really? - Come on, just go!
Come on, just leave now, Kuya!
You really, really can't!
Damn!
What was that?
- Hey. - Sounds like someone was barking.
What are you doing there, dear?
What?
She's hiding from Estong, Ninang.
Looks like he already left.
But I really feel bad for Kuya Estong.
Seems like he really wants to talk to you.
I'm also doing this for all of us.
I think he'll understand.
Oh, my.
Here we are.
- Hey, ma'am! - My order's here.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
Give me ma’am’s order.
Here, Kuya.
Here you go, ma'am.
Thank you.
Here.
You get tips, okay?
Especially you.
Uh...thank you so much!
Feel free to order from us again, ma'am.
Oh, sure.
Only if you're on the menu.
Uh...
Sure, ma'am. When you order from us,
We'll deliver it to you ourselves.
- It's not a problem. - Just kidding!
But I'm not joking about you being handsome, okay?
I'm sure...
You've had women hit on you.
Thank you!
Oh, no, ma'am.
Not at all.
Actually...
Women either leave him or avoid him.
Oh, really?
Well, okay. Thank you!
Let's go, Kuya.
You know, bro...
I wonder where Ysa is.
I really want to talk to her.
Actually, Kuya...
I already tried fishing for info from Adel, but there's nothing.
But...
Let's try to find some clues.
Wait, hold on.
Kuya, Kuya.
I think...I think they're just somewhere nearby.
I can't. It's so hot.
I can't take it anymore!
- Bro, just a moment, okay? - Okay.
Hey, he's here.
Uh...let's go home, Ate?
Uh...
Cacai! Adel!
- Let's go home. - No, it's even hotter at home!
- Where are you headed? - I don't wanna go there.
Not now.
Hide me.
Are you okay, Cacai?
Me?
Oh, clearly not.
'Cause, you know, it's hot. I can't.
Want to go to our café? It's cooler there.
- It's open air. - No!
No!
I don't like it there.
- But why? - No!
Why not?
No! No! No!
You know why?
Oh.
You might get offended, though.
But
It's up to you if you want to be offended.
From what I've heard...
If it weren't for café,
The two of you wouldn't have met.
Does Ysa regret meeting me?
I think I'm not the right person to ask.
But I'll give you a little clue,
Just so you know.
She wants you to focus on yourself,
Because she feels that you haven't really gotten over your ex.
What made her say that?
Oh.
That I don't know.
That's all I know.
And that's all I'd say.
Well, then.
- Ate, let's go? - Don't tell her about what I said, okay?
Don't tell her it came from me.
- Let's go? - Come on, let's go.
Let's go!
Where is it?
Here's the address, bro. 1272-B Gumamela Street, Brgy. Kinamulatan.
Bro, where are you? Are you gonna be much longer? We're hungry.
There, we just need to keep our wrists relaxed.
Then, we just need to trust our creativity.
- Ysa? - and imagination.
You can almost do anything.
And then, you can just let it flow.
Keep your wrists relaxed.
So that everything can flow,
Which makes painting more fun.
- Ysa! - And then...
And you can just...
Just keep on trusting your creativity.
- You can also... - Ysa.
Recreate whatever you see in our nature.
Like that!
Ysa.
Oh, wow!
Your work looks beautiful.
Ysa, Ysa.
Estong!
Didn't see you there.
Yes.
What are you doing here?
I am just making a delivery.
How 'bout you?
- I see. - What's up?
Well, I'm busy teaching painting.
Oh.
Wow! That one on the swing is so cute!
Ysa, are you free later?
I was hoping we could talk.
Could you check my work, please?
Hey, I got here first.
No, I did.
You're such a show-off, huh? Mine's better.
No, mine is.
I got here first, okay?
Do you always have to be the bad guy?
Your work looks terrible.
Why are you always like that?
- Your work doesn't even look good. - Hey!
What are you two arguing about? You're so noisy!
You better not disappoint me with your work!
Oh, wait. It's not yet finished.
I'll work more on mine.
Always so much to say.
And you!
Why are you still here?!
You! Back off!
Stay away from Ysa!
Bogart...
I thought we were buddies?
Maybe you can help me out.
Please.
What's going on?
How should I know?! I just read something in Ysa's diary...
It said that
You're still unsure about what you want in life!
Because of my ex.
Because I have no direction in life.
That's why Ysa
Doesn't want me to pursue her.
Bogart, maybe you can—
Maybe you can talk to her. Please, Bogart.
Yeye don't know anything.
Yeye!
It's your best friend!
Best friend!
Why?
What's going on?
I can't.
They all told me
Not to talk.
Come on,
We're best friends, right?
We made a pinky promise, remember?
Do you want something? A lollipop?
You love lollipops, right?
Or...balloons?!
Some balloons! You wanna play?
So, what did she say? What’s the problem?
Can you tell it
To your best friend?
No! Can't talk.
Yeye is a good girl.
No!
Hello?
- Kuya, where are you?! Where's my order?! - Ah...yes, ma'am! I'm still on the way.
I'm still on the way. I'm really sorry.
Alright, okay.
I haven't written anything yet.
To solve this problem...
We have to find "X."
"X" again?
It's always "ex", huh?
Oh, man...
You know, they really need to move on.
Focus. Enough with the jokes.
I'm focused, okay?
If you end up failing the admission test...
Don't blame me, okay?
Maybe you're the one who's gonna fall.
Oh, I mean...
Fail.
Gosh, you're annoying.
Do you still have questions?
Actually, I do.
Are you still single—
Yes.
Yes, I'm still single.
I mean Ate Ysa.
Oh...
Why?
Nothing.
I just want to help Kuya out.
I also want to know why they can't be more than friends.
How can I answer that? I'm not Ate Ysa.
But...
I'm sure you know something.
Both of you are close after all.
Oh, I get it.
So you came here to fish for information?
You didn't come here to review.
- Just go home. - Hey.
I came here for both.
Adel,
Please, just tell me.
I just want to know the answer.
You're close to Ate Ysa.
Jayden,
Even if I know something,
It's not my place to tell you.
The truth is,
I feel bad for your Kuya Estong.
But Ate Ysa has it worse.
You won't get it.
It's too complicated.
Very.
That complicated?
Yeah.
It's more complicated than what I'm teaching you.
At least this one has a clearer answer.
But for her situation...
I don't have one for that.
Alright.
You don't have to answer me,
If it's that complicated.
But as for you and me...
Everything's clear, okay?
That's why I'm helping you review, okay?
- Oh, right. Yes, the review. - Please, let's focus now, okay?
Wait,
I haven't even written anything yet.
Miss, how much is this?
The price tag is there, can't you see?
It's already right there, miss. The price tag's big.
I even had that printed out.
Kuya.
Are you stalking your ex again?
What, are you getting back with Jean?
Are you giving up on Ysa?
I spoke to some of
Ysa’s other personalities earlier, Pops.
I asked them why Ysa's avoiding me.
They brought up my ex.
She think I might not be over my ex yet.
Look, Pops. I'm stalking Jean.
I'm looking at her pictures.
But I can't feel anything for her anymore, Pops.
I'm not even hurt anymore.
That's why I'm sure I've already moved on.
Are you sure, Kuya?
Like, if Jean talked to you,
You wouldn't need closure anymore?
We already had our closure, bro.
I just couldn't accept it at first.
I'm also okay now.
I'm happy wherever she is right now.
I didn't even think about her until
They brought up my ex.
So is there another reason?
I just read it in Ysa's diary...
It said that you're still unsure about what you want in life!
They also told me about...
My direction in life.
Are you going to take the exam again, Kuya?
I need to.
I need to find some direction in my life,
So...
I'm going to try again.
That's right.
However...
You should make decisions
For yourself,
Not for other people.
I already know that, Pops.
I just have to deal with both right now.
I can do both, right?
It's more fulfilling to have a goal
When it's not just for yourself,
But for other people too.
Especially if...
You love the person.
So,
You're really not going to Australia anymore, Kuya?
That's still the plan, bro.
But for now, while I wait...
I'll just work as a virtual assistant.
That's right. That's good.
At least, you have a lot of options.
Actually, Kuya...
I talked to Adel earlier
About why Ate Ysa's been avoiding you.
She said it's difficult.
It's complicated.
That's why she doesn't want to tell us herself.
I remembered what Tita Barbs told me.
She said I don't know Ysa well enough yet.
But...
Kuya, haven't you met all of her personalities already?
I honestly don't know.
Well, whatever it is.
I just want you to know that...
I'm so proud of you, son.
For all of the decisions you're making.
Thank you, Pops.
Come on, group hug!
- Group hug? - Come on.
But I'm a grown man and—
Come on, we haven't done this for a long time.
It's really okay, Pops.
There's no one around, okay?
Have you taken a bath yet, Kuya?
Of course I did, stupid.
Of course you get first dibs,
Because you're a very customer of mine.
Thank you, Adel.
Uh...wait,
Let me find something that would look good on you.
That one! That would look really good on you.
This could work for Belle.
It's amazing, isn't it?
They're just clothes, but somehow...
Each one has its own personality.
At least with clothes,
You can tell right away which personality they suit,
Who they belong to.
But this body...
It's a mess.
So hopefully, when Belle comes back...
She'll finally be able to accept all of us.
Don't worry, Ate.
She'll understand eventually.
Hopefully.
What about Estong?
Will he understand once he knows
The real reason I've been avoiding him?
Go on, pick some more.
Maybe there's something else you might like.
That's cute, too.
Ysa!
Do you want me to handle him?
Estong.
Ysa.
How are you?
I'm okay.
How about you?
Just keeping myself busy.
But sometimes...
I can't help but think of you.
I missed you.
Ysa...
I just wanted to see you.
Maybe we could talk.
I know.
I know there are some things
You don't want to tell me.
They might be complicated.
Whatever it is,
I'll respect that.
I won't push you anymore.
But...
I just hope you won't keep on avoiding me.
Estong.
I'm sorry.
I just don't want things to get messy.
How would things get messy?
My feelings.
Does that mean...
Um...
Estong, there are still some of my personalities
You haven't met yet.
And I don't know...
What will happen when
She comes out and you meet her.
So...
Let's just leave it at that.
All I know is...
I know it's better for all of us
If my feelings don't get complicated.
That's why I don't want to complicate things.
That's why we should just stay friends.
You can't court me. You can't...
Just friends, really.
I hope you understand.
If... if that's all we can be...
Okay.
We'll just be friends.
That way,
You won't have to avoid me anymore.
It's alright for me.
Estong...
Ysa, don't worry.
I understand.
Thank you for understanding, Estong.
So,
We're good now, right?
You don't have to avoid me anymore or even...
Hide somewhere
Where I can see you anyway.
Alright.
So,
Can you paint at Love U Café again?
Depends. If there's free coffee.
So all it takes is free coffee. Fine, then.
I'll take care of it.
Uh...
Spanish Latte for Ms. Ysa.
Cold with 75% sugar.
Estong,
Thank you.
Sorry.
It's good.
Just the right balance.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
So, what are you going to paint today?
Ah.
I might just sketch for now.
I see.
Okay, if you need anything,
Just let me know...
Just call my name and I'll be there.
- Thank you. - Estong!
Looks like you two are okay now.
Maybe just as friends, Pops.
Well, it's better to be friends
Than enemies, right, son?
Right.
Well...
It's world peace for the both of you.
There's a customer.
Hello!
Lorenz?
Lorenz.
What are you looking at?!
What?!
Lorenz.
- Kuya, Kuya, it's Ate! - Dear?
Are you okay?
Estong!
Ysa!
Ysa, what happened?
Are you okay?
Uh...please excuse us.
She's okay, she's fine.
Sorry about that.
Ysa?
Ysa.
Are you okay?
Easy.
Where am I?
You're in my room.
Uh... no, no. You're thinking about it wrong.
Uh... I had to take you upstairs because
There were so many people downstairs.
Many people were staring at us and
That's after you passed out.
The door and windows here are open too.
So if anyone walked by, they would've seen the two of us.
- I promise, I didn't do anything wrong. - Estong!
I know.
I know you.
You okay now?
Mhm. I'm okay. I just...
I just felt dizzy.
Didn't know you liked books.
A little bit.
Those are mostly reviewers.
For what?
I want to try taking the licensure exam again.
Actually, it's going to be my fourth attempt.
You'll pass this time.
I hope so.
Do you...
Have someone to study with?
No,
It's just me.
Do you...
Want me to help you?
Really?
I can quiz you
Or even...
Tell me what you've learned,
What you've studied, so you'll remember it better.
I can't pay you for your time, okay?
You helped us with the exhibit, right?
- Wow! - So pretty!
Impressionist. That's me.
This is your soul.
- Didn't I tell you to pose properly?! - Okay, okay, wait.
- So pretty! Clock it! - Yes!
This time...
I want to be the one to help you.
Alright, but no taking it back, okay?
Until you pass.
Until I pass.
Okay.
Let's study.
Do you like Estong?
Let it go.
We all knew he wouldn't be able to help it, okay?
What's debt?
Uh...first word...
Debit?
Debit increases...
E—?
Enterprise?
Ex—?
Ex— expenses.
Debit increases...
Assets, dividends.
Perfect!
What's FIFO?
First-In, First-Out.
What's LIFO?
Last-In, First-Out.
What is COIL?
Charity of...
Oh, that's way off. Really, really off.
No connection at all.
I give up.
Go on, review it.
And then I'll film you.
- If you need it, just play it back. - Alright.
Okay?
Weighted Average Cost...
Thank you.
When you wake up,
I'll show you just how loud you snore.
Thank you, Estong.
This guy,
The one who snores so loudly.
This is the person who helped us.
Kuya.
Oh, just set it down right here.
Thank you.
It's on the house, okay?
- Okay, Kuya. - I'm paying for our bill, okay?
Okay, let's start. What...
Do you mean by obligation to do
And obligation to deliver?
An obligation to deliver
Is when you are required
To give something.
Like an item or money.
While obligation to do is
When you're required
To render a service.
So I guess your obligation to deliver
Was to buy me coffee, since I'm helping you with your review.
Yes.
And...
I feel like I have an obligation to...
Stay by your side so you don't fall asleep
While we study.
You're so corny.
- Go away! - Why?
That was a good one.
Keep your distance!
This is okay.
- Move some more. - Huh?
Move a little bit more.
Okay, game. What's next?
Okay, next.
What are the acquistion methods?
- The acquisition methods... - Okay?
Of business...
Wait, okay?
The acquisition method...
I'm sorry, Estong.
I see it...
I can feel the effort you're making.
But I'm not the right personality
To make decisions for all of us.
Alright.
Thank you so much for your time and I'll message you
For the revised materials and updates
At the end of the day.
Sound good, mate. Looking forward to it.
Okay.
Take care.
Hey.
You're already here.
Hey. What are you up to?
Uhh...I'm just filling out a form.
What form? What is it?
Secret! I don't want to jinx it.
It might not happen.
Oh, so you're keeping secrets now, huh?
You also have your own secrets, right?
So we're even.
Right.
Oh!
Get ready. Time for our review.
Let's take a break first.
Huh?
Why?
Because
You promised you'd teach me how to paint, remember?
Me?
Yes.
Oh?
I don't think I remember that.
Hey, I remember that very clearly.
You said you'd teach me how to paint.
Maybe...
Maybe that was another personality?
Oh, really?
Just kidding.
I remember it.
So,
Are you going to teach me how to paint now?
Let's do it now? Come on.
Oh!
I made a mistake.
I pushed the brush too hard.
Oh.
It looks bad now.
No, it won't be.
Just because you made a mistake
Doesn't mean the painting is ruined.
Isn't that how it works?
It depends.
Besides, we're using acrylic.
It dries quickly, so if you make a mistake,
Just let it set, then paint over it.
And sometimes...
The problem is not the color,
It's the value.
Value?
Yes.
The value.
How light or dark it is.
Sometimes, you can get the color right,
But if the value is off, it can still look wrong.
This is also pretty complicated, huh?
Not really.
Just needs a lot of practice.
And sometimes...
Even the things you think you did wrong,
Can end up making the painting even better.
You can add some more...
You can also lessen it.
All of those things can contribute to the composition.
Uh...
I thought that whenever you make a mistake...
You have to erase it.
Just because you made a mistake...
Doesn't mean you have to erase it.
Right.
Wait a minute.
Can you try this stroke here?
Go ahead, let me see how you do it.
Let's see.
- Just like that. - Oh, that's how you do it.
Like this?
Why do you have paint on your nose?
I didn't notice that before.
Did you just put that there?
Hey, you think you're with Yeye or something?
You can't win me over with those antics.
Right. You're not Yeye.
So what's the yarn for?
That one there.
- Oh! - What's that for?
This?
You can use this for texture.
So you just dip it in the paint,
Then...
You can do it like this.
So like...
I saw somewhere that they make it thicker, like this.
Yeah.
Then, they also use it for this!
- You cheeky... - Like this, right?
Like this.
Uh...
We just brought you something to eat.
Thank you!
Come on.
I thought
They were just doing a painting tutorial.
So why does it look like they're flirting?
Let them be.
They look like they're having fun.
What do you mean, "let them be"?
Didn't we have an agreement with Ysa?
Love, they're just friends, right?
Oh, yeah. Not obvious at all.
Weren't we like that before, too?
Come on.
That's the thing, okay?
Look at us right now.
Well, we ended up getting married.
You know, love...
Maybe we should just talk to them later, okay?
We should.
Relax.
Uh...Ysa.
Yes?
I just want to say thank you.
I learned a lot from you.
Me too.
I also learned a lot from you, Estong.
Let me help you.
Ysa.
I really love you.
You don't seem hard to love.
Yeye wants cake.
There's a crazy person here.
I'm scared of you.
You're crazy!
No.
Ysa?
I'm not Ysa!
My name is Belle!
Belle.
Ysa!
Estong, don't.
There's something you need to know.
Ysa...
Is just one of the personalities.
It's Belle.
She's the real Ysabelle.
What?
Belle is...
The first of them all. She’s the original.
I still want to get to know Belle.
But they're not the same person, okay?
They have different personalities.
Their Nanang even said that...
Belle isn't okay yet.
What? Do you want Ysa to get confused again?
But I want to see you again.
You promised you'd come to my exhibit again.
Ysa.
I mean...Belle.
You?
You know me?
Just because you're friends with my personalities,
Doesn't mean we're friends too.
You know, I really thought you wouldn't talk to me anymore.
Because you're Belle now. You're so different from—
I'm so different because of my condition?
Wow! Look at you!
All dressed up! The outfit...
The shoes, the hair.
Looks nice, right?
Belle?